<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lisp on Abizer Nasir</title>
    <link>http://abizern.org/tags/lisp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lisp on Abizer Nasir</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://abizern.org/tags/lisp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hakyll New Post With Emacs</title>
      <link>http://abizern.org/2014/hakyll-new-post-with-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abizern.org/2014/hakyll-new-post-with-emacs/</guid>
      <description>When this blog was created using Octopress, a new post could be created by simply running rake new_post in the Terminal. There is no such convenience in Hakyll, which is currently used as the generator. A small thing, but I wanted to fix it.
I could have created a similar Rake task, or shell script to do this, and there are even examples to be found on Hakyll&amp;rsquo;s site. But since I&amp;rsquo;m usually in Emacs when I want to write a new post, I thought it would be a good excuse to write a little lisp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up for Lisp on OS X</title>
      <link>http://abizern.org/2013/setting-up-for-lisp-on-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abizern.org/2013/setting-up-for-lisp-on-os-x/</guid>
      <description>This is how I roll, you might choose a different path.
 Install Emacs. Get a nice, modern pre-built binary from Emacs For Mac OS X. It even supports fullscreen mode
 Install Emacs Prelude which provides a useful, opinionated emacs environment which is easily configured.
 Install clisp. I use homebrew so brew install clisp takes care of that for me.
 Install quicklisp; from Terminal go to a temporary directory and download quicklisp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Reason To Learn Lisp</title>
      <link>http://abizern.org/2012/a-reason-to-learn-lisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abizern.org/2012/a-reason-to-learn-lisp/</guid>
      <description>A short video from a live demo of Emacs from Web Rebels in Oslo 2012.
As the description says: &amp;ldquo;Crappy sound. Swearing. A noisy bar&amp;rdquo;, but an example of strong content overcoming presentation difficulties.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>