<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ruby | Abizer Nasir]]></title>
  <link href="http://abizern.org/categories/ruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://abizern.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-06T18:54:50+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://abizern.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abizer Nasir]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Correcting Brace Layout]]></title>
    <link href="http://abizern.org/2012/12/30/correcting-brace-layout/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-30T11:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://abizern.org/2012/12/30/correcting-brace-layout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote a <a href="http://abizern.org/fixbraces/">small rubygem</a> called <em>fixbraces</em> to
move the opening brace of a conditional to the same line as the opening
statement.</p>

<p>So now I can correct all the Xcode generated stubs that look like:</p>

<p>``` objective-c
- (void)someMethod
{</p>

<pre><code>// some code here
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>Into my preferred format:</p>

<p>``` objective-c
- (void)someMethod {</p>

<pre><code>// some code here
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>Which fits with my personal coding standards.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Live Coding]]></title>
    <link href="http://abizern.org/2012/08/20/on-live-coding/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-20T12:34:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://abizern.org/2012/08/20/on-live-coding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read somewhere that part of the popularity of
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_West_Wing">The West Wing</a> was that it was
entertaining to watch smart people solve difficult problems. I think that's part
of the reason why I find watching live coding videos so entertaining - It's more
fun to watch someone solve a problem than doing it yourself.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There are plenty of screencasts you can find - <a href="http://youtubecom">YouTube</a> is
an obvious one, but don't forget <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>

<p>Some good ones to watch are the
<a href="https://peepcode.com/screencasts/play-by-play">Play-By-Play</a> series produced by
<a href="http://peepcode.com">Peepcode</a> These screencasts have a developer solving a
problem set by the host as he talks to them about the choices they make and the
tools they use. Mostly Ruby / Railsy, but there are exceptions - Zed Shaw and
Python, Ryan Singer designing a UX workflow for the Web, Kyle Neath on UI
Workflow, and the latest has Tim Caswell creating a node.js web app.</p>

<p>These are not only interesting screencasts, with plenty to learn from, but I
find they are great for background noise. I work at home, and having the sounds
of a keyboard clacking and techy conversation pushes back the silence. Also,
when you look at a tutorial type blog post - or something on GitHub, all you see
is the finished product. But when you watch someone working, you realise that it
doesn't come out fully formed like that, it sort of evolves. The same way that
you evolve code.</p>

<p>I did my own small one about
<a href="http://abizern.org/2012/04/09/reverse-words-with-haskell/">reversing words in Haskell</a>
a few months ago and I found that it's harder to do than it looks. I credited
<a href="http://codinguncut.com/">Jonas Tullus</a> as an influence for that screencast and now
see that he has started <a href="http://codinguncut.com">Coding Uncut</a>, where he takes
on a problem and screencasts his solution in Haskell. This is harder to do than
the Peepcode ones, because without anyone asking you questions you become more
self-conscious about vocalising your thoughts.</p>

<p>Some of the things I've picked up from watching these are:</p>

<ul>
<li>It's okay to spend your time looking up the documentation. Knowing roughly
what approach to take to a solution and then looking up the details is more
important.</li>
<li>It's faster to try something and see what happens rather than overthinking
everything from the beginning.</li>
<li>Version control is not an optional extra (okay, I already believe this, but
it's nice to see that I'm not the only one).</li>
<li>It's not the tool that matters - Emacs, Vim, JEdit, Paper and Sharpie - but
how you use it.</li>
<li>"It's not about the code. It's your understanding of the problem that you're
working on." - Zed Shaw</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
