<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Abizer Nasir</title>
    <link>http://abizern.org/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Abizer Nasir</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://abizern.org/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocoa Coding Conventions</title>
      <link>http://abizern.org/notes/cocoa-coding-conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abizern.org/notes/cocoa-coding-conventions/</guid>
      <description>Purpose Consistent coding conventions are one way to keep code readable and maintainable. Written coding conventions provide a handy reference for the times when one can&amp;rsquo;t remember what conventions apply.
This is a living document, and if I find that I am breaking the conventions I&amp;rsquo;ve set for myself, then I&amp;rsquo;ll update the document to match what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. This is more a record of my choices than a rod for my own back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Notes</title>
      <link>http://abizern.org/notes/emacs-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abizern.org/notes/emacs-notes/</guid>
      <description>Installation Emacs brew install emacs --cocoa --srgb  .emacs.d These work for my dotfiles, based off Emacs Prelude, which should be cloned to ~/.emacs.d. There are no submodules in this repository.
Install with the customised script
curl -L https://github.com/Abizern/prelude/raw/master/utils/installer.sh | sh  General C-_, C-x u Undo, Cancel last command C-x, C-f Visit file C-x C-i Insert contents of file in buffer C-x C-s Save buffer C-x C-w Save buffer as&amp;hellip; &amp;lt;revert-file&amp;gt; Revert to last saved version C-x p Visit buffer under point C-f, C-j Turn off ido-mode in minibuffer M-; Comment active region (comment-dwim) M-/ Hippie expansion C-M-/ Completion on current word M-q Format text to paragraph C-x \ (align-regexp) C-c C-w Backward kill word S-return Smart open line below C-S-return Smart open line above C-g Quit command in the minibuffer C-u Prefix argument M-j Join the next line to this one</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>