<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: NSCoder Night | Abizer Nasir]]></title>
  <link href="http://abizern.org/categories/nscoder-night/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://abizern.org/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-20T14:59:06+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://abizern.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abizer Nasir]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NSCoder Night London Now Has It's Own Page]]></title>
    <link href="http://abizern.org/2011/04/14/nscoder-night-london-now-has-its-own-page/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T20:01:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://abizern.org/2011/04/14/nscoder-night-london-now-has-its-own-page</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's been over a year that I've been running the NSCoder Night meetings in
London from here, but I've now moved it to a site of its own. You can now get
all the information from
<a href="http://nscodernightlondon.com">NSCoderNightLondon.com</a>.</p>

<p>Blog style entries never really worked. I hope that having everything together
in just a few pages on a site makes it easier for people who want to turn up.</p>

<p>I hope that it floats up higher in Google Rankings as well. This will also make
it easier for people who want to turn up.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NSCoder Night London - Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://abizern.org/2009/09/25/nscoder-night-london-report/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-25T14:11:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://abizern.org/2009/09/25/nscoder-night-london-report</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/15729248@N00/3952499655"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2671/3952499655_33ed3b7b29.jpg" alt="NSCoder Night" /></a></p>

<p>The first London NSCoder Night was a success!</p>

<p>Eleven people turned up, travelling from as far as Brighton and Reading to join
in the fun. There was a mix of indies, learners, small Mac shops and students.</p>

<p>We started off upstairs at the <a href="http://bunchofgrapesborough.com/">Bunch of Grapes</a> and then moved to the outside area for more room. The tables outside are at a comfortable height for standing around so people were able to move around to different groups. There was a food, drink and talk and the laptops came out a few times as well.</p>

<p>We decided that this is going to be a regular event, held at the same place on the <strong>third Tuesday of the month</strong>. Next time I'll book a table upstairs so we can sit down more comfortably. You don't need to tell me you're coming, but I'd appreciate an idea of how many people are going to make it so I can reserve approximately the right number of seats.</p>

<p>Thanks everyone for coming out. It was a great night and I hope you all went home with as much enthusiasm for coding as I did.</p>

<p>So, until the next time; follow <a href="http://twitter.com/nscodernightlon">@NSCoderNightLon</a> on Twitter and subscribe to the <a href="http://tinyurl.com/m5g6jb">iCal calender</a> to stay up to date.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NSCoder Night London]]></title>
    <link href="http://abizern.org/2009/09/21/nscoder-night-london/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-21T23:02:08+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://abizern.org/2009/09/21/nscoder-night-london</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's surprising that there isn't an <a href="http://nscodernight.com">NSCoder Night</a>
chapter in London. There is a monthly CocoaHeads meeting in Swindon, and the UK
Mac Dev meeting once a month in Central London, but I think that there is a gap
for an evening of coding in a social setting.</p>

<p>So, in the spirit of "If you build it, they will come" I'm going to try and get
this started. So, this Tuesday, September 22, from about 7, let's get together
at the <a href="http://bunchofgrapesborough.com">Bunch of Grapes</a> pub just behind London
Bridge Station
<a href="http://maps.google.co.uk/maps?source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=bunch+of+grapes+borough&amp;sll=51.50722,-0.089006&amp;sspn=0.006357,0.016973&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;radius=0.36&amp;split=1&amp;filter=0&amp;rq=1&amp;ev=zi&amp;ll=51.507454,-0.088019&amp;spn=0.006691,0.016973&amp;z=16&amp;iwloc=A&amp;iwd=1&amp;cid=16443485918241557592&amp;dtab=2">map</a>. Bring
a laptop (charged) and you can either sit and code or just chat with anyone
else. You can work on what you want. You don't have to show anyone what you're
working on; but feel free to ask and answer questions.</p>

<p>But, this is still just an experiment. Don't know whether it will be a weekly or
a monthly event. I'm not even sure about the location. I was there last week and
the WiFi was a little flaky. There was a party upstairs so it was busy, but
there was a high turnover (as you would expect for a pub near a train
station). I still managed to get a table. But, unless we try and get together,
we won't be able to answer these questions.</p>

<p>So, Come along tomorrow night. Follow
<a href="http://twitter.com/nscodernightlon">@NSCoderNightLon</a> on Twitter and subscribe
to the <a href="http://tinyurl.com/m5g6jb">iCal calender</a> for future meetings.</p>

<p>See you there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
